## Manvi SinghFeatured Resume

HR Manager seeking roles in Human Resource Management, Talent Acquisition, HR Operations, Payroll Management, Event Management, Vendor Management, Recruitment Management, Employee Onboarding, Statutory Compliance, Policy Formulation, Performance Appraisal

Current Designation: HR Manager

Current Company: Apmosys Technologies

Current Location: Mumbai

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mumbai

Functional Area: HR / Administration / IR

Role: HR Manager

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 3 Months

Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [HR/Industrial Relations]

Key Skills: HR Manager, Human Resource Management, Talent Acquisition, HR Operations, Payroll Management, Event Management, Vendor Management, Recruitment Management, Employee Onboarding, Statutory Compliance, Policy Formulation, Performance Appraisal

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: 1c1be8136c19d6f656Last Active: 18-Sep-20Last Modified: 18-Sep-20

Jump to SectionWork Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Over 9 years of experience in the field of Human Resource Management in diverse organizations and sectors.

Responsible of Human Resource Planning and Management- Talent Acquisition,
Training & Development, Induction, HR Operations, Resource Management,
Payroll Management, Event Management, Employee Engagement, Team
Management, Vendor Management etc.

Responsible, loyal, reliable, solution-focused professional with excellent interpersonal and rapport-building skills.

Self-motivated professional who achieves results and has a superior ability to coordinate and perform several projects simultaneously.

Work Experience

Apmosys Technologies as HR Manager

Oct 2017 to Till Date

**ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES** 

Recruitment & On-Boarding:

Managing a team of 2 people for screening the resumes. Monitoring team member?s performances and motivating them to create the highest levels of efficiency and productivity.

Network and communicate with internal hiring managers and determine recruitment needs, outside vendors (including employment agencies and consultants) and candidates.

Managing end to end processes for hiring and induction, Pre-joining formalities and Post joining formalities of employees.

Retention of potential employees and planning for mobilization / demobilization in association with Department Head.

Personal Documentation & Records:

Supervision of proper filing and maintenance of employee personal records of around 500 employees. Follow up with the employees for submission of records and change in record documents.

Maintain the confidentiality of HR matters (salary/appraisal details, HR investigation details, disciplinary action details etc.)

Attendance & Leave Records:

Responsible for Preparing Consolidated attendance report of employees through Online Leave Management Portal.

Cross verification of leave taken, leave balance and leave carry forward to next financial year.

Updation and tracking of Listed Holidays in Online Leave Management Portal.

Confirmation:

Interacting with Team Leaders/Project Managers/HOD?s regarding the feedback of their team members performance.

Tracking and Issuance of Confirmation/probation Extension letter to Probation employee.

Payroll Management:

Managing compensations, salary processes through online portal.

Managing mid-year and yearly salary revisions.

Statutory Compliances & Disciplinary Actions:

Maintaining the PF and ESIC entries of eligible employees.

Coordinating with the consultant for generating PF and ESIC challans and doing the payments.

Issuance of Warning letters.

Tracking and sharing the Disciplinary action cases details with the director.

Policies Formulation & Execution:

Working with senior management to formulate & implement various HR policies; review of existing policies; standardization of HR policies across the organization and blue-print for implementation.

Quarterly Performance Appraisal Reviews and Awards:

Designed parameters to assess the performance across all the levels and prepare quarterly performance report of all employees.

Ensured that employees Rewards & Recognition is rolled out as per company policy.

Training and Development:

Promoting a culture of organizational learning in which best practices are shared

across all verticals.

Coordinate and facilitate employee development training as per training plan,

transfer processes and internal movements.

Conducting managerial/technical trainings to enhance the managerial, technical

and soft skills of the employees.

Grievance Redressal:

Conduct skip level meeting, one on one sessions to ensure employee satisfaction.

Addressing grievances reported by employees within the predefined time frame as

well as ensuring adherence to code of conduct by all employees and maintain log

of employee grievances.

Maintaining cordial employee relations by providing personnel counseling.

Staff Culture Development Activities:

Managing utilization of the HR budget and planning staff retreats such as monthly

birthday celebrations, leaders party, annual function etc.

Exit Formalities:

Taking care of the exit formalities of the resigned employees with the completion

of exit interview process and F&F settlement.

Pragati Software Pvt. Ltd. as Sr. HR Executive

Feb 2015 to Oct 2017

Maharashtra Industries Development Institute (MIDI) as HR Manager

Sep 2014 to Jan 2015

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Physics, Chemistry and Math) from Meerut University in 2007

PG: MBA/PGDM (HR/Industrial Relations) from Symbiosis, Pune University in 2019

## ^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

MS-OFFICE

MS-EXCEL

MS-POWERPOINT